JORGE IVAN RODRIGUEZ

Sydney, Australia

Phone: 0468757314 | Email: ivany9@hotmail.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/Jorge-ivan-2022b4113 | GitHub: https://github.com/ivany9 |

Portfolio: https://ivany9.github.io/reactPortfolio/

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with a background in Systems Engineering. Recently obtained a formal qualification as a web developer from the University of Sydney Boot Camp. Creative problem solver who is passionate about learning and expanding knowledge in new technologies. Experience in front end and back end developing with a focus on developing apps that are functional and user friendly. Comfortable working as both part of a team and autonomously, while drawing on strong communication and technical skills to bring projects to life.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SQL, NoSQL, Microsoft Power Apps.

Applications: GitHub, GitLab, MongoDB, MySQL, Heroku.

Tools: Express, React, Node, Handlebars, Query, Bootstrap, Redux.

PROJECTS

Tools Finder | GitHub: https://github.com/ivany9/toolsfinder | **Deployed:**

https://toolsfinder.herokuapp.com/

- An app which allows users to find and rent tools from people in their local area. Users can also list tools for rent setting their own price and availability.
- Sole developer, front end and back end.
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Node.JS, jQuery, React, Mongodb, graphql

Fitness Tracker | GitHub: https://github.com/ivany9/Fitness-Tracker | **Deployed:** https://fittness-track.herokuapp.com/

- An app that focuses on fitness allowing the user to view, create and track their daily exercise and progress.
- Sole developer.
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Node.JS, express.JS, Mongodb.

Weather-Dashboard | GitHub: https://github.com/ivany9/Weather-Dashboard | **Deployed:** https://ivany9.github.io/Weather-Dashboard/

- A weather app that provides up to date current and future weather forecasts for cities around the world. The user can search for a specific location and find the forecast for that city.
- Sole developer.
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, jQuery, API, Fetch, Localstore

Car Enthusiasts | GitHub: https://github.com/ChristopherBz/Car-Enthusiasts | **Deployed:** https://car-enthusiasts.herokuapp.com/

- An app for car enthusiasts that uses the latest technologies and allows users to share car photos and stories.
- Co-developed, front-end designer.
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Sequelize, Express-handlebars, dotenv package, multer.

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Project 2022

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Sydney, Australia

- Building a MERN app for a business called Salsa Town which will allow clients to book dance classes.
- Building reusable code.
- Back end and front end.
- · Testing code.
- Working closely with the client to develop an app that meets the needs of the business.

Volunteer

SOFTWARE ENGINEER 2022- 2022

One Community

Los Angeles, California

- Integration of the front-end and back-end of the web application. React- Redux
- Building reusable code.
- Working as a team member to fix bugs and provide support.
- Testing code.
- Working in Express.js, MongoDB, GitHub, React-Redux, Jets.

Carpenter 2020 – 2021

BKH Group

Sydney, Australia

- Provided carpentry and building services on domestic and commercial projects
- Built and maintained relationships with all stakeholders and worked successfully as part of a team on site.
- Ensured all work was finished in a timely manner to a high standard in line with customer requirements.

Carpenter 2015 – 2020

Self Employed

Sydney, Australia

- Managed self-employed business providing carpentry services and creative solutions to building projects.
- Problem solving and collaboration with all stakeholders to ensure projects were carried out as required.
- Trained and provided leadership to apprentice carpenters and labour support.

Computer Numerical Control Programmer

2015 - 2015

Pinetown Precision Engineering Australia Pty Ltd

Sydney, Australia

- Engineering and programming of CNC machinery, operating and setting CNC Lathes and running Fanuc controllers.
- Collaborated with all stakeholders to ensure deadlines were met and projects executed on time.

Production Manager

2006 –2014

Partescol

Bogota, DC, Colombia

- Engineering and programming of CNC machinery, operating and setting CNC Lathes and running Fanuc controllers.
- Responsible for managing the production department, organising logistics required for importing and exporting products and ensuring safety procedures met required standards.
- Built and maintained relationships with internal and external stakeholders.
- Responsible for marketing and sales, including organisation of international product shows.

EDUCATION

University of Sydney, NSW, Australia Bootcamp Certificate, Web Developer

2021

Universidad Externdado de Colombia, Bogota, Colombia Certificate of International Commerce 2009

Politecnico GranColombiano, Bogota, Colombia Bachelor of Systems Engineering 2000 – 2006

SENA Colombia Certificate in AutoCAD 2D & 3D 2000